-[birds chirping]
-[theme music playing]
♪ Hilda ♪
[woman vocalizing]
[snarling]
[roars]
[growls]
Whoa! You're not a crazy rumor after all.
-You're real!
-And also hungry.
[growling]
-Last to join, first to get eaten.
-What? Ahh!
[grunts]
[hound growling]
[growls]
Frida!
[sniffs]
[exhales]
Run!
[barking]
[roaring]
You know, all he wants
is something to eat.
-No kidding.
-So let's feed him.
[Frida] Feed him what?
-Please don't say us.
-These!
[growls]
[grunts]
-Come on!
-[David whimpering]
-[flashlight clicks]
-[Raven Leader] Hilda?
David!
And who's that? Frida?
It's-- It's the Black Hound!
He-- He's here and he's huge!
-He tried to eat us.
-What?
But he's eating my snacks instead,
so everything's fine.
For now.
[distant roaring]
We need to get everyone
out of here, immediately!
[siren blaring]
Attention, Sparrow Scouts,
due to an unexpected,
um, wildlife situation,
we are breaking camp early,
but we will do so
in a calm, orderly fashion.
[distant roar, howling]
The Black Hound!
-Oh, no! We're all gonna be eaten!
-The Black Hound!
Remember, you should be packing,
not panicking.
[grunting]
[sighs]
[David grunting]
-[sighs] Here, let me help you.
-I've got it.
[grunting]
-You were right, you know.
-About what?
About my new so-called, huh, friends.
[David grunting]
Oh, for goodness sake,
will you just let me help?
Fine.
Hold the end... like that.
I-- I wish I could have spoken up
to those marra the way you did.
Oh, yeah, that felt pretty good
until we almost got eaten
by a giant hound.
I'm sorry. I've been acting like an idiot.
Finish packing this, please?
I'll be right back.
-What?
-Where are you going?
I've got to find Tontu.
I can't leave him out there
with the Black Hound.
He could get eaten.
I'm so out of the loop.
Uh, who's Tontu?
I'll explain later.
[Raven Leader] Hilda!
What on Earth are you doing?
You will stay here and pack up
your gear this instant
or you will not be allowed
to come on future camping trips.
[sighs]
[kids chattering]
[Hilda] Mum's here.
My parents don't know I'm out here.
-Uh, could you give me a lift?
-Of course.
Ah, I'm just so relieved
that everybody's safe.
Not everybody.
-What?
-Nothing.
Oh, I'm sure they'll catch
that thing soon.
A creature that big
shouldn't be too hard to find, right?
Right.
I know you're disappointed
about not getting the camping badge,
but don't worry.
You've earned plenty
of other badges this year.
-Huh?
-[sheepish laugh]
-What are you doing?
-Shh.
All right, Frida, here we are.
[Hilda] This is Tontu.
He's a nisse?
Yes, and he was thrown out
of his house by mistake.
You're sure he didn't do something bad?
-I'm sure. Trust me. He--
-Hilda... I trust you.
Okay.
So, does that mean
you'll help me look for him?
Yes. I'm in.
-See you tomorrow?
-See you tomorrow.
Wait.
Just to follow up on what your mum said
about your badges,
do you even have a single badge?
No.
Then I have
the perfect plan to get you one.
Of course I want you to earn
the Fund Raising badge.
But maybe I should go along.
That thing is still out there, remember?
Good point.
But there are safety patrols
in every neighborhood now.
-And he's only been seen at night.
-Even my parents are okay with it.
See? We'll be fine.
[sighs] All right,
but stay together at all times
and stick to the busy streets.
You may end up with even more badges
than I earned my first year.
Maybe. [sheepish laugh]
Good luck, Sparrow Scouts.
[David] Hello, we're collecting
for Sparrow Scouts' jumble sale.
Tontu said he used to live
in a yellow house with a duck pond
before he was kicked out.
[growling]
-[Hilda] Hey, who are those guys?
-[Frida sighs] Safety patrol.
They're searching for the hound.
What are they going to do to it
when they find it?
Oh, you're not dead.
Uh, why are you dressed
like a Sparrow Scout?
Because I am a Sparrow Scout.
Oh, good! I've got a donation.
Wow! People are being really generous.
No, not my Fluff-bun!
I mean, ahem...  I don't care. Um...
Keep him.
It's never a good idea
to throw away your real friends.
[gasps] Tontu?
[echoing] Tontu, are you in there?
-[cat screeching]
-[Twig growling]
[Twig grunts]
Twig?
-[grunts]
-Tontu!
Hilda!
It's Tontu!
Uh, just make sure you meet us
at the Sparrow Scout Hall by 3:00
or else you won't get credit
for the badge!
Sure thing!
[pants]
Tontu!
-Yes, that's me.
-No, it's not.
I assure that it is.
-Well, I'm looking for a different Tontu.
-But we're all called "Tontu."
[chuckles] That's confusing,
but good to know.
How come you're out here anyway?
Nisse are being banished all over town.
Do you know why you're all being banished?
[nisse 1] We don't talk to each other,
you know.
[nisse 2] No, nisses don't enjoy
each other's company.
Yep, I've seen that.
[nisse 3] I was kicked out,
and it wasn't my fault!
[nisse 4] My house-man
threw me out for no reason.
[nisse 5] I was framed.
I didn't trash that house.
A lot of other nisses
are saying the same thing.
[nisse 5] I'm sure
the rest of them are lying.
I'm not totally sure how this works,
but isn't there a lot of unused
or hidden space outside?
Can't you make a cozy nest there?
[nisse 5] The place of which you speak
is vast and cold.
Who knows where one would emerge?
The nisse who ventures there
is likely never to return.
Maybe the guy you're looking for
went back to the woods.
Why are you so bothered anyway?
He's no worse off than when you met him.
He's not your problem.
[bell tolling]
Oh, no! I'm supposed to be
at the Scout Hall right now!
Come on, Twig!
[panting] Sorry I'm a little late.
Raven Leader just left.
We stalled for as long as we could.
But at least you found Tontu, right?
No.
[news anchor] News just in.
Trolberg city officials say
they have reason to believe
that three people
have been eaten by the hound.
Details to--
We don't need to hear that before bed.
Let's focus on something positive,
like the badge ceremony tomorrow.
Oh, right, I almost forgot.
I knew you'd make a great Sparrow Scout.
I guess it just runs in the family, right?
[chuckles]
I'm really very proud of you, you know?
I think I'll go to bed now.
[thunder rumbling]
Oh, Mum is going to be so disappointed.
And today I blew my last chance at a badge
because I was busy looking for Tontu.
I can fix that.
Great! How?
You both need to sign
a Disappointment Deferral Agreement.
And we can add in additional clauses
that address hidden resentments
or blaming tendencies.
It's very simple, really.
Alfur, humans just don't work that way.
And thus we arrive at my own feelings
of disappointment.
-[distant howling]
-[whimpers]
Here we are, all cozy, and poor Tontu
is out there in the rain with that thing.
My guess is that thing
is actually a barghest.
What's a barghest?
A kind of wild, giant dog!
Though, what it's doing in Trolberg
is a mystery.
Barghests usually live
deep in the mountains.
If that's the case, then he's lost
and probably scared.
[hound howling]
And definitely hungry.
You're sure it's okay to get a ride
with David and Frida?
Mum, I'm sure.
Then I'll go straight to Scout Hall
after my client meeting.
I am so excited!
[laughs nervously]
See you at the badge ceremony.
[door opens, closes]
You know, I think I'll walk
to the ceremony and look for Tontu.
Maybe the day won't be a total loss.
[bus hisses]
[duck quacking]
[quacking]
Yellow duck, yellow house!
Hello?
Sorry, I already gave my donation
to some Sparrow Scouts just the other day.
Oh, no, it, it's not that.
I was just passing, and I was wondering
did a nisse ever live here?
Well, of course, dear.
Not anymore, though.
Would you mind if I asked what happened?
Well, I caught him stealing, didn't I?
Stealing? Are you sure?
Do you think you could possibly
have been mistaken?
Oh, no.
There was the most dreadful racket,
like someone was smashing up my kitchen.
I came down to see what was going on,
and there he was.
He'd ransacked the whole place
looking for something to steal.
He must have gotten bored with
all the things he'd swiped over the years
because that was everywhere, too.
That's why I said I had
so much junk for your jumble sale.
I mean, donations.
Thank you very much for your time, ma'am.
-[clattering]
-[voice murmuring]
-[Hilda] Tontu!
-[Tontu] Oh, hello.
Oh, so you're fine.
I've been so worried.
Oh, you don't even care.
[Tontu] Can't believe your mum
let you go out on your own
with that monster on the loose.
It's not a monster. It's a barghest.
And Mum thinks I'm getting a lift
to the ceremony with David and Frida.
I couldn't bring myself to tell her
that I'm not getting any badges
because of you, basically.
-Why lie about something like that?
-Why lie about why you were kicked out?
That nice lady said you trashed her house.
[Tontu] She's lying.
I'm completely innocent. Hmph.
I know you're capable of it.
Every nisse says the same thing.
But they're all probably lying.
And of course
that's what they'd say about you.
Ugh! I've spent so much time
looking for you and worrying about you
because I felt I ought to help you.
Now I don't know if I should've bothered,
and you're not even grateful that I did.
[Tontu] What? This is
what I look like when I'm grateful.
Oh.
I have to go.
Listen, why don't you check
this place out?
The Scout Hall must have
loads of Nowhere Space, right?
If it's not good,
just meet me afterwards, okay?
Up next: Frida.
You have achieved your level three
Helpful and Friendly badge
along with your Fund Raising, First Aid,
Stonework, and Young Entrepreneur badges.
I think we can all agree
that's very impressive.
[Raven Leader]
Next: David for his Fund Raising...
-[hound growling]
-...and Cycling badges.
[Tontu gasps] Uh-oh.
Oh, and also his Friend to Insects badge.
-[cricket chirping]
-There's a bug on your head.
And that concludes
this year's badge ceremony.
[applause]
-[Tontu] Hilda!
-[kids gasp]
[crowd gasping]
-Tontu?
-[Tontu] We've gotta go, now!
[Tontu grunts]
[crowd gasps]
[growling]
-[all screaming]
-[boy] It's the Black Hound!
-[all shouting]
-[Raven Leader] Please keep calm!
Keep calm, everybody.
-[Tontu] Oh...
-[growls]
[Tontu] Come on! [grunts]
[growling]
Hilda!
[Tontu] Jump! Through here!
-[Tontu grunts]
-[cat yowling]
[Tontu grunting]
In here!
[Tontu panting]
[grunts]
Frida's lost book?
[snarling]
[barking]
Ah!
[Tontu] In here!
[Tontu shouts, panting]
Oh! This is Frida's room.
[Tontu] Come on!
-In here! [groans]
-Wait!
[pants] This is my house!
[growling]
Actually, it's my house.
[growls]
So I would ask you kindly to leave.
[sniffing]
Jellybean?
[panting]
[gasps] Jellybean!
It's you!
[both] Jellybean?
This is my dog Jellybean.
I haven't seen him since he was a puppy.
I found him a long time ago
when I was little.
He was lost.
I did what nisses do with lost things
and took him home.
I looked after him in secret for a while,
but when my parents found him,
they took him off me
and I never saw him again.
I've never understood why.
They must have known
what he'd grow up to be.
I never knew he would get so big!
[Tontu] But is he dangerous?
He ate people, didn't he?
Yes. Three at last count.
Hold on.
[whispering]
[gagging]
[all screaming]
So I guess he sort of ate them.
Hilda? Hilda!
Oh, are you all right?
-[sniffing]
-[gasps]
It's okay, Mum. This is Jellybean.
-This explains everything.
-[Tontu] Really?
He was taught how to use the nisse spaces
when he was a puppy,
so of course he's been using them
to hide and move around the city.
Every time he goes through a nisse's nest,
he's so massive,
he takes everything with him.
And then he trashes whatever room
he happens to arrive in.
It all happens so fast that he's gone
before you know what's going on.
That's why you're all getting kicked out.
He's been framing you.
Are you saying that's what happened to me?
Wouldn't I have seen him?
[chuckles] It's a wonder you can see
anything at all with that haircut.
[police siren wailing]
What's that?
[sirens blaring]
-Those are the men looking for the hound.
-You have to get rid of them.
Hilda, maybe it's best if we just--
Mum, no!
I know what you think,
but he's really a very dangerous animal.
He's a puppy.
He's no different from Twig.
-Hilda...
-[sighs]
I know I don't have a badge to prove it,
but I am still a friend to animals.
He hasn't hurt anyone
and I won't let anyone hurt him.
-[siren chirping]
-[hound whimpers]
[whines]
[whimpering]
-He's panicking.
-[nisse] How far are the city walls?
If I could get him outside,
maybe they'd let him go.
Follow me.
[tires squealing]
Jellybean!
[whimpers]
Everyone, seat belts.
[nisse] Jellybean!
[tires screeching]
[Tontu grunting]
Mum, go faster!
[Mum] Oh, I can see the town gate.
We're almost there.
[Tontu] What happens
if he catches up with us?
[tires screeching]
I can't see a thing!
-[all shout]
-[Mum] Oh, the brakes aren't working!
[Tontu whimpers]
-Tontu, quick, take my hand.
-[Tontu] Whoa, whoa, wait!
I know what you're thinking.
It's too dangerous.
-Tontu, we're going to crash!
-[Tontu] Okay, okay!
One, two, pull!
[Tontu shouting]
[groans]
[sighs]
What on Earth just happened?
[Tontu] That place
is the place we never go to.
Sorry for dragging you through there.
It was necessary.
[chuckles] Don't apologize.
You saved our lives.
And we escaped, too.
-But... where are the others?
-We got separated.
They could be
thousands of miles away right now...
if they even made it out at all.
Here, I've got something for you.
I finally found my sewing kit,
so I thought I'd make an addition.
Look, I'm sorry that I pressured you
about getting badges.
I already know that you're the kindest,
bravest, most selfless girl
it is possible to be.
You don't have to prove anything.
Thanks, Mum.
[Tontu clears throat]
Your hot chocolates are ready.
No marshmallows for you.
Loads of marshmallows for you.
This report will set off
a golden age of elf exploration!
[gasps] Just think
of all the missing paperwork
that may have fallen into Nowhere Space!
[doorbell rings]
That's probably David and Frida.
[Tontu] I'll get more hot chocolate.
[grunts]
I'll get some biscuits and Dragon Panic.
Is that a kind of a badge?
Please find a reason
for this not to be on my arm
before the next Sparrow Scout meeting.
-Maybe Tontu could, you know, "borrow it"?
-[Tontu] Not a chance.
[Frida] I know!
Twig could snag it with an antler.
[Alfur]
Or we could pay a visit to the lindworm
and have it lightly scorched.
[woffs calling]
[elves murmuring]
[Wood Man whistling tune]
What happened?
[Wood Man] This was once
a cozy little house.
The girl who lived here
befriended a giant.
-I guess she learned her lesson.
-Not likely.
Odds are... she'd do it again.
[folk music playing]