-[birds chirping]
-[theme music playing]
♪ Hilda ♪
[woman vocalizing]
[David whimpers]
I hate dark, creepy tunnels.
They tend to be filled
with things that are horrible.
You'll be thanking me
when we get our Sparrow Scout badges
for subterranean urban exploration.
That's not a real badge.
Not yet, but Raven Leader
will be so impressed with us
that she'll have no choice
but to create one.
Ooh! [laughs]
We'll be the first Sparrow Scouts
to earn a badge before it's invented.
-[gasps] There should be a badge for that.
-[gulps]
-[thuds]
-[Frida screams]
-Frida?
-[screaming]
Hilda!
[shouting]
[panting]
[groaning]
Flipping head lamp!
[screams]
At least the last thing I ever did
was be right!
[screaming]
[exhales]
[screams]
Oops.
-Sorry, Warren.
-[doorbell rings]
[David's mum]
David, your friends are here.
First order of business: bug check.
Bug check complete.
Now what are we going to do?
We could ride bikes.
Too boring.
Why ride bikes
around the same old streets
when there's a great big world out there?
There's so much we've never seen,
so much we don't know.
There's mystery everywhere you look.
Like, who's that girl?
And what dastardly scheme
has she been up to?
That's just some new girl on our street.
Yes, but what's her name?
I don't know.
Aha! See? She's a mystery.
Hilda, when you lived in the wilderness,
you knew everyone
because it was just you and your mum.
But here in Trolberg,
there's a lot of people we don't know.
You just have to get used to it.
I'm telling you,
there's something odd about her.
She's always alone.
She never talks to anyone.
I've never seen her go into a shop.
[chuckles] Have you noticed
the more you talk about how odd she is,
the more odd you sound?
She's just a teenager.
Most teenagers are a bit weird.
So? People think elves are weird,
but they're actually quite fun.
Well, Alfur's fun.
The rest are rather dull and tedious.
Come on!
[groans]
[panting]
Wow, she moves fast
for someone who walks so slow.
Gah! How'd she do that?
You said yourself, teenagers are weird.
This is getting too spooky.
Let's just go to the park.
You scare awful easy for someone
who's always got a bug on him.
Sorry, I'm a bit jumpy.
It's probably on account
of having nightmares all week.
All week?
What do you think is causing them?
Uh, don't take this the wrong way,
but... you, obviously.
Me?
You're always dragging us
to see something weird
or telling us
about some creepy thing you read,
like how Trolberg has so many rats.
And that they get their tails tangled up
and become the fearsome Rat King.
That's why I had a nightmare about rats!
I'm sorry, David.
I didn't mean to scare you.
Then why did you call it "fearsome"?
What's wrong with "fearsome"?
Not to worry.
I'll help rid you of your nightmares.
Really?
-How?
-We're going to find the Rat King!
[groaning]
-[distant boat horn blaring]
-[seagulls screeching]
[David] How is this meant to help me?
[Hilda] The best way to overcome
your fears is to face them.
Like trolls. When you actually meet one,
you realize they're not scary at all.
Well, not that scary,
except when you're staring
into that giant, drooly troll mouth
and consider
they could eat you in one bite.
At least I know
what my next nightmare will be about.
Once you've seen enough scary things,
you don't get scared anymore.
That's one of the perks
of being an adventurer.
-Come on.
-[gulps]
[David whimpering]
This is just like my nightmare.
Less scary in real life, isn't it?
-[rumbling]
-Uh, what's that?
[all screaming]
[screaming]
[screaming] Help!
-Ah! Ooh.
-[screaming, grunts]
[exhales]
[spits, clears throat]
[sighs] See? There was something
to be frightened about.
Yes, but it wasn't rats.
So, in a way, we're both right.
[stammering] Ra-- Wha...
-What is it, David?
-Ra-- Ra--
[rumbling]
[Rat King] Ah, visitors.
Have you secrets to trade
with the Rat King?
Secrets?
We are the keepers of all secrets
rats overhear from humans,
and we always wanna hear more.
Have you secrets to trade?
I suppose the polite thing
would be to tell him a secret.
After all, we are guests in his home.
Who's got a good one?
[both whimpering]
Okay, okay, I'll do it.
-[whispering]
-Uh-huh, uh-huh. Oh!
Ooh, yes! Fascinating!
We never would have guessed.
What a delicious secret!
Oh! [laughing]
And have we got a good one for you.
[laughing]
The one responsible
for your friend's nightmares
is the teenage girl.
The one walking around the neighborhood?
-I knew there was something off about her.
-[Rat King laughing]
Oh, we're so bad!
No pudding for us.
[cackling]
[chuckles] He's fun.
[crickets chirping]
[electricity buzzing]
[snoring]
-[static crackles]
-Frida, do you read me?
-Over.
-I'm in position.
But, Hilda, how could this girl
be causing David's nightmares?
-Over.
-I don't know.
That's why this time,
we cannot lose her. Over.
[shouting]
Sorry, Bertrand.
I'm not myself.
Frida, something's happening.
Do you see anything? Over.
[zaps]
[gasps] She's here.
David, get in position. Over.
[panting]
This way!
She was just here, I swear.
[growling]
Go, Twig!
[gasps]
[doorknob rattles]
[David over radio] Target acquired.
Way down at the end
of Nutten Avenue, turning left.
[gasping]
[thuds]
Also, I just remembered
I'm terrified of heights.
Over.
[Frida] Hilda!
-[tires screech]
-Get on!
Um, that's all right.
Don't worry, I've got a helmet for you.
Quickly, we're losing her.
[grunts]
Twig's got her scent.
She's headed for the Huldrawood.
-What?
-Yeah, she can do that.
Stay, Twig.
Hilda, wait!
We're so close.
We can't stop now.
No, I mean,
according to the Sparrow Scout manual,
you really ought to use a bowline knot.
Oh, good thinking!
[girls giggling]
And as David's head fell off his body
and tumbled screaming down the rocks,
he realized his head was bouncing
directly into the mouth of another troll!
[girls laughing]
[laughing] That's too good.
Hey, listen here, you.
Oh, my.
That was eerie.
Yeah.
I-- I mean, I'm not scared,
but I can see how you'd think that.
[David groaning]
She told my nightmares to her friends?
That's not fair.
I deserve a royalty or something.
Don't you think?
Definitely.
But first, we need to find out
just what's going on.
[thuds]
I believe you'll find that book
to be of interest.
[Hilda] "Tales of the Marra."
"The marra are nightmare spirits
who are said to haunt the Huldrawood."
Look, that's them all right.
I don't understand.
How did the librarian know exactly
what book we needed?
That's her job, isn't it?
True.
It says here that the marra
visit sleeping humans at night
and create nightmares out of their fears.
So, I'm not just having nightmares.
There's also an evil spirit in my room.
I think I felt better
before you started helping.
Look, David.
It says here the marra will pass over you
if you strap yourself into bed
with a leather belt.
No good.
I am deathly afraid of belts.
Luckily, it's never been a problem
since I'm very good
at fitting into trousers just right.
Belting yourself into bed
is no way to live.
I'm going to have to talk with this marra.
We're going to settle this
once and for all.
[David] Well, Hilda is going home now.
I am going to bed early
as soon as Hilda leaves,
which she is doing now.
[door closes]
Hold on, there.
Oh, there's no bug on you.
Ha, never mind.
Good for you, son.
Phew!
[Twig squeaks]
[trills softly]
Shh!
[whimpers]
[panting, gasps]
[Mum] Hilda.
You've got a bug on you.
I bet you picked it up
from that David kid.
[grunting]
You were right,
that bowline knot is fantastic.
Thanks. And your story worked.
My mother thinks
I'm sleeping over at your house.
Good.
Here's the plan.
I'll sleep in David's bed
so the marra will think I'm David.
You'll hide under David's desk
where the marra won't see you.
Just to make sure the marra
doesn't go after you,
you'll belt yourself
into the sleeping bag.
Now, the marra always enter
through the keyhole,
so Alfur will guard it.
According to Alfur's records,
the marra has no paperwork on file
with the elves,
so she won't see him when she comes in.
[bones crack]
[Hilda] Alfur will wake you up,
even though you can't see him, either.
[whispers] Frida!
[Hilda] You'll use the marra's weakness,
the leather belt,
to hold her in place
long enough for us to talk.
-[screams]
-Dream on.
Like I'm gonna let myself get trapped
by some little kid?
-Huh?
-Yep!
[both grunting]
You!
You're that crazy girl
who's been chasing me all over town.
And you're the one who's been giving
my friend David nightmares.
Uh, duh!
His nightmares are the best.
There's so much to work with.
He is scared of everything.
[laughing]
That's not funny.
[sighs]
Oh, whatever. You like scaring him, too.
The Rat King told me David was, like,
practically crying
when you went to see him.
You know the Rat King?
I'm trying to help David
get over his fears,
you're just making them worse.
So, I want you to leave David alone.
Yeah, right.
The girls love his nightmares.
I'm not giving that up.
Oh, so you pick on David
because it's easy.
I bet your friends
are secretly laughing at you
for not stepping up your nightmare game.
-Excuse me?
-Don't you think they'd be more impressed
with a nightmare
from someone harder to scare?
Like who? You?
Unless you're afraid of a challenge.
Ha! Go to sleep, then.
You'll see
whose nightmare game is on point.
Fine.
You can take your best shot...
if you promise to leave David alone.
Mm...
deal.
But if you wake her up before I'm done,
the deal's off.
[gulps] Got it. Heh.
-Sleep tight.
-Oh, I will.
I'm gonna sleep so tight, you won't
believe how... tight I'm going to s-sleep.
[Hilda groaning, growling]
-Well?
-[groaning]
I'm trying.
It's not easy falling asleep
on purpose, you know.
[snoring]
-[snoring continues]
-[growling]
[Twig whines]
[yawns] Is that Hilda snoring?
[both screaming]
[clock ticking]
[groaning]
Ugh!
[snoring softly]
[yawns] Mum, are you up?
Hilda, you let the spiders in!
It's all right, Mum.
I can use these for my bug collection.
Maybe I'll get a Sparrow Scout badge.
You're not frightened?
Not really.
They're cute in that ugly sort of way.
[loud thud]
[roars]
[forest giant] Mmm.
You'll make a fine between-meals snack.
[snorts, roars]
Forest giants aren't known to eat people.
Are you trying new things
because your life's in a rut?
Eating people won't fill that void.
Whoooaf!
-[woffs calling]
-Hey, "whoaf" sounds a bit like "woff."
Is that why we call you a "woff"?
I bet it is.
What scares you, crazy girl?
But you must have a...
secret.
Hilda! Down here!
This way! Hurry!
[screams] Ooh!
We don't ride woffs, we ride bikes.
That's right.
The street hasn't got a woff lane, has it?
W-- Wait!
Ah!
[panting]
[screams]
[tires screech]
Hilda, can't you ride a bike?
Even I can ride a bike.
[screams]
[marra laughing, echoing]
Ah! [panting]
It's not my fault!
I'm not from here!
[demonic voice] No, you're not!
[screaming]
Huh, I guess she's not coming.
[panting]
[screams]
Ah!
Help!
[screaming]
[grunting]
[screaming echoes]
[door opens]
-Where's Hilda?
-[Frida] Shh!
Don't wake Hilda,
or else David will keep having nightmares.
What are you talking about?
It's okay, though.
Uh, she's... she's fine.
No! [grunts] Help!
Help! Help!
[screaming]
[Hilda groaning]
I can't make her do this for me.
If she can handle them, then so can I.
[Hilda screaming]
-Hilda! Wake up!
-[panting]
Hilda, are you all right?
You were crying out in your sleep.
An adventurer
never cries out in her sleep.
Uh, but what are you doing
in David's bedroom?
[giggles]
[birds chirping]
Mum wants me to stay close to home
for a couple of days.
Sorry you had to wake me.
Did you have a nightmare again?
Actually, no.
Sweet dreams all night.
Literally about sweets.
-The marra didn't come back?
-[marra] Nope.
It's no fun giving nightmares to someone
who's brave enough to ask for them.
Wait.
How did you know?
[exhales] About my secret?
I know the Rat King, remember?
We trade each other's secrets on the reg.
See you.
[Frida] What secret?
Uh, it... it doesn't matter.
But it did remind me
that seeing as I don't really know
how things work around here,
I'm awfully lucky
to have you two as friends.
So, from now on, I won't force you to do
anything scary you don't want to.
But we do want to.
We like that about you.
Really? Y-- You, too, David?
I suppose I don't mind,
as long as I get
to have dreams about sweets.
So, got any new adventures planned?
Well, if it's not too boring...
you want to teach me how to ride a bike?
[theme music playing]