[Wind rushing, pastoral music playing]
[Distant train whistle blows]
♪ The angels have gone ♪
♪ The songs have gone silent ♪
♪ You're sinking like a stone ♪
♪ Before the tide ♪
♪ The river runs co-o-ld ♪
♪ The fight is over ♪
♪ Still the haunted ruins
of night call your name ♪
[sighs]
Mm-hmm.
Oh, yes.
[Wind rushing]
Yes.
Into the unknown.
[Crowd cheering]
[School band playing march]
[Cheering intensifies]
GREG: Good-bye!
Thank you, Old Lady Daniels.
Good-bye, Gregory, and please
don't call me Old Lady.
Yes, sir, young man.
- Hey, Wirt, whatcha doing?
- Nothing.
I was helping Old Lady Daniels
rake some leaves
in exchange for candy.
Greg, it's Halloween.
Candy is free.
Old Lady Daniels says nothing
in this world is free.
Oh, hey, and look!
I also got this rock.
[Deep voice] Hey, Wirt,
want to learn some rock facts?
[Normal voice] So, you want to
go look for frogs with me like
you said you would awhile ago
and haven't done it yet?
Nah. I'm busy.
Is that bee named Sara?
W-what?
Your tape says, "For Sara.“
You gonna give it
to Sara the bee?
I-I want to, but I can't.
Can I see it?
Yeah. It's just a tape.
Hmm. Yeah. OK.
I'll give it to her for you.
Oh, Greg! W-wait! No, no!
Oh, look at you.
What are you supposed to be?
It's an elephant costume.
[Trumpeting]
Pbbt! See my trunk?
- Yeah. That's cute.
- I'm an egg.
Yeah. Everybody knows
you're an egg, Rhondi.
- Shut it, Kathleen.
- Whatever.
So, what are you, Wirt,
some kind of gnome?
Uh, I cl... I don't know.
Well, it's...
See, I was...
I thought I'd just, like...
Hey, what's this?
That's Wirt's tape for Sara.
Ooh! Wirt loves Sara!
You want us to give it
to her for you?
It's for a different Sara,
not the one you're
thinking about.
Yeah, Wirt's talking
about mascot Sara,
the one he's been
looking at all night.
What?
- Ooh! Wirt's got a crush on Sara.
- Ha ha ha!
Well, you better act fast
'cause we heard
Jason Funderberker
is gonna ask her out
at the Halloween party tonight.
Jason Funderberker?
ALL:
Yeah.
But I... but, um...
You OK, Wirt?
Yeah. Everything's... everything's
Jason Funderberker.
- What?
Uh, uh, Jason Funderberker.
I-l got to go.
GREG:
Bye!
[Frogs croaking]
Is the dove never
to meet the sea
for want of the odious mountain?
- Hey. So... frog hunt?
- Huh?
I keep hearing ribbiting
around town,
and I think it's the last frog
of the season.
No. I just want to wallow
in misery.
Sara and Jason Funderberker.
Ach.
That guy's got his act together.
He's the total package.
I can't compete.
You're the total package
too, Wirt.
I bet she'll really
like your tape.
We never got the tape back!
I can't let her hear that tape!
Why not?
That tape has got poetry
and clarinet on it, Greg.
Poetry and clarinet!
Sara and Jason Funderberker
are gonna start dating,
and then they'll hear that tape,
and then they'll just sit
and listen to it and laugh
and laugh and laugh and laugh.
Why don't you ask Sara out first?
That way...
No, no! Ugh!
Why did you have
to take the tape?
My life is crumbling
all around me!
OK. I think we should
put our frog hunt on hold
and go get that tape back.
Guys, where's the tape?
We put it in Sar♪s jacket
for you.
- Aah!
- You better hurry.
She's changing
in the track shack.
- Ha ha ha!
- Excuse me. Oh, no.
WIRT:
The jacket!
[Both panting]
Hey! Are you trying
to spy on Sara?
Uh... no. Run, Greg!
Hey, Sara, be careful, huh?
There's some real creeps
out there tonight.
Thanks, Jimmy.
OFFICER: Hey, you two robbers,
you're under arrest.
Nah, I'm just kidding.
Happy Halloween.
Heyl Stop running
in the streets!
Just kidding. Happy Halloween.
WIRT: There she goes.
Let's get her.
Yeah. Let's get her.
No. W-we're not gonna
get her like that.
- What are we doing?
- We're just gonna get the tape back.
Oh, yeah.
Let's go in after her.
Oh, I can't.
I wasn't invited to this party.
- I'll go in.
- You weren't invited, either.
- Oh.
- Yeah, man, there's lots of
bat-and-ball games besides baseball...
one old cat, two old cat,
stoolball, roundball...
Why are you talking to them?
Aah!
Oh. Hey, guys.
I don't know what he said,
but I-it wasn't true.
- Oh, hey, Wirt. How's it going?
- Hi, Wirt.
Oh. Uh, yeah.
Well, see you around, guys.
I used to be
really good at ballet,
but my mom wanted me
to be a wrestler.
- Oh, Wirt. You're here.
- Well, I...
I was just asking
if you were here.
Oh, wow. Heh.
Oh, hey, we're gonna
go to the graveyard.
Oh. Are you gonna
do something there?
Nah. We're just
gonna hang out
and drink
age-appropriate drinks.
- Like juice?
- Yeah, whatever.
Age-appropriate stuff
that's not illegal.
- Hey, you should come.
- Uh, I don't...
Hey, Sara, are you ready to go?
Hey, Jason Funderberker.
Oh, hey, Wirt.
Let's go, Sara. Ohh...
- You coming, Wirt?
- No, no.
You... You go have fun
with Jason Funderberker.
OK, but if you want to stop by
later or something...
Mm. Bye, Wirt.
Sayonara, Jason Funderberker.
[Gasps]
Sar♪s jacket!
My jacket. Thanks, Wirt.
Well, see you, hopefully.
Bye. Ohh...
SARA:
You're limiting the universe
to only things humans
can understand.
Well, you're limiting
the universe
by limiting the possibility
of human understanding.
Oh, yeah. Maybe.
- Sara?
- Yeah?
Do you believe in ghosts?
Why?
'Cause there's one
right behind you!
Aw, I'm just kidding.
It's OK, Funderberker.
- Ha ha ha!
- Stop! You hit me!
Come on.
[Croak]
[Gasps]
Wirt, you tricked me!
I didn't know this was
a frog hunt all along.
- It never was a...
' [gasps]
GREG:
A witches' gathering!
And so then a guy
with an axe showed up!
[Laughter]
Ugh. Everybody loves Funderberker.
What do I do?
I'll pretend to be a
dead elephant and distract them
while you get the tape.
WIRT:
Please just stay here.
And so she kept getting
closer and closer.
- What are you doing?
- Jason.
GIRL:
Oh, Jason.
[Growls]
- Go, Greg. Do it.
- OK.
Uh, you can let go
of my hand now.
Oh, yeah.
You could hold my hand,
Funderberker. I don't care.
Whooooo!
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
Hey, isn't that
Wirt's little brother?
Nooooo.
I'm the headless elephant.
[Trumpeting]
Little guy. Ha ha ha!
Is Wirt here, too?
Over there!
- Huh!
- There he is.
- Wirt, we can see you, man.
- Oh, Greg.
Oh. Hey, guys.
Greg! There you are.
Totally wasn't
spying on anybody.
I was just looking for...
[siren wails]
- What's going on here?
- Huh?
Is this some kind of
witches' gathering?
You're all under arrest.
- Run'.
- Hey, hey! I was just kidding.
Slow down, kids.
You're gonna trip or something.
Run, run, run! Run, run, run!
Where do we go?
That Way!
Greg, why did you say this way?
I thought I heard a frog.
- This is private property.
- Uh...
Hey, don't climb up there.
That's dangerous!
Get down here before
you hurt yourself!
- Huh?
- It has my name on it.
- Ohh...
- Let's go listen to it.
- Ha ha ha!
- Noooooooooooo!
Kids, really,
get down from that wall.
That's it. That's the end.
Oh, darn it. No.
I mean come down this way.
-
Oh, once again,
you ruin my life.
Who? Me?
Ugh! You and your stupid dad!
You're always prodding me,
trying to get me
to join marching band.
Uh, yeah!
If you join the marching band,
you can hang out with Sara more!
That ship has sailed, Greg,
thanks to you
messing that up, too.
[Croak]
[Gasps]
Hold that thought, Wirt. Hmm.
What are you doing now?
Ha ha! We found our lucky frog.
We got to name him
for good luck.
[Croaks]
I don't want to have anything
to do with your or that frog!
OK. I'll try to think of a name myself.
[Train approaching]
Ugh. I'm leaving.
Hmm?
Huh?
[Train whistle blowing]
Aah!
♪ There's an old black train
a-comin♪
♪ Scraping 'long the iron ♪
♪ You don't need
no ticket, boy ♪
♪ It'll take you in its time ♪
[female humming]
Huh? Where... Huh?
Oh. You're awake.
Here. Eat some dirt.
[Pbbt!]
Uh, Beatrice?
You know my daughter!
Where is she?
I don't know.
[Croak]
Somebody left you and that frog
on the doorstep.
Beatrice.
But have you seen my brother?
- No, I'm sorry.
- I gotta go!
You're in no shape to head
into that snowstorm, young man.
Here, here. Eat more dirt.
Thanks. Come on, guy.
Let's go find Greg.
At least wait until the storm
dies down a bit.
You'll be no good
to your brother dead.
I was never any good to him
alive, either.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
If you see Beatrice again,
give her a hug for us.
Yeah.
[Mysterious piano music plays]