[Wind blowing]
[Train whistle blows]
[Honking]
[Chirping]
[Gobbling]
[Blowing raspberries]
It's almost morning.
We should've found
a town by now.
This is the way the woodsman
told us to go, right?
Pbbbt! Have you listened
to anything I've been saying?
For the last couple hours,
I've been saying...
Pbbt! Pbbt! Pbbft! Pbbt!
Well, that settles it.
I'm gonna walk up 10 feet ahead of you.
FEMALE BIRD: Help!
GREG: Huh?
FEMALE BIRD:
I'm stuck!
I hear something!
It's probably nothing.
Hey, look.
"Pottsfield, 1 mile."
A town! Let's go this way.
OK, let's go this way.
Not... ugh.
Hello? Hello?
' HEY. You.
- Who? Me?
- Yeah, you.
- Oh. Hello.
It's you again. I'm stuck.
Help me out of here,
and I'll owe you a favor.
Whoa! I get a wish?
No, no, no. Not a wish.
I'm not magical.
I'll just do you a good turn.
Can you turn me into a tiger?
Um, no.
I just said I'm not magical.
It doesn't have to be
a magical tiger.
Greg, stop talking to a bush.
- OK.
- Huh?
Thanks. I owe you a favor.
So, um, you two are lost kids
with no purpose
in life, right?
Uh-huh.
How about I bring you
to Adelaide of the Pasture,
the Good Woman of the Woods?
She could help you get home.
Oh.
N-no, no. No, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Magic talking birds leading
us to fairy godmothers
in the mysterious...
I'm going to Pottsfield.
Yeah, we're going
to Pottsfield.
- Come on.
- What about the favor?
I'll think of my wish later.
BIRD:
Ugh.
So let's small-talk.
My name's Greg. What's yours?
Beatrice.
My brother's name is Wirt.
Who cares?
And my frog's name's
Wirt Jr.,
but that may change.
OK. That's great.
How about you and I ditch
your brother?
Mmm. Maybe later.
So is it nice being a bird?
- Nope.
- Oh.
Do you like waffles?
No, waffles make me sick.
I eat m-maggots.
- Aah!
- What?
How can you not eat waffles?!
Aah!
I t ' What?!
- S
WIRT:
Aha!
Civilization, see?
Now... huh? What the...
[grunting]
All right. Let's rejoin society.
Hello? Hello?
Hmm. See anybody?
No.
Oh, I see you.
Yeah, I see you, too, Greg.
Hey, not to be obnoxious,
but an abandoned ghost town
doesn't seem like
it's gonna be that useful
getting you guys home.
Ahem. There's got
to be somebody...
somewhere.
Excuse me? Anyone here?
Hello?
Oh. Sorry.
Uh, I'm looking for a phone.
Um, I'm sorry.
Heh heh.
BEATRICE:
Did you find anything?
No. Where's Greg?
- Do you hear that?
- Huh?
VOICES:
♪ Let spirits meet ♪
♪ Around the barn
of Pottsfield town a'
-
" Huh?
♪ Oh, Heidi, pour
more golden mead I
♪ Yon is the Maypole dance I
♪ A ribbon to wind my soul a'
♪ And to bind her
to the dance a'
What the...
Oh, pardon me there.
Say, you folks ought to
don your vegetables
and celebrate
the harvest with us.
Uh... oh! You're
wearing costumes.
Well, sure.
Pumpkins can't move
on their own, can they?
Ha. No. Yeah, no.
Good thing I didn't
take this off.
You guys find this place
as creepy as I do, right?
So it's some kind of weird cult
where they wear
vegetable costumes and dance
around a big thing.
They seem nice enough.
OK, you're in denial.
That's fine,
but I'm just saying something
feels off about this place.
[Creak]
Well, maybe I can find
someone here
who will give us
a ride home.
Greg, you stay out of trouble.
Beatrice, thank you,
but you can leave.
I can't leave.
I'm honor-bound to help you
since you guys helped me.
That's the bluebird rules.
Uh, okay.
Beatrice, would you care
for this dance?
No, thanks.
No, thanks, no, thanks.
I said no, thank you.
Say, aren't you
a little too early?
What do you mean?
I mean, it doesn't
seem like you're ready
to join us just yet.
Join you?
Yeah, no, I'm just
passing through.
Folks don't tend to
"pass through" Pottsfield.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. It's nice here.
Um, I'm really just looking
t-to leave here
as fast as possible.
Eh, what, what?
Leave Pottsfield?
Who wants to leave Pottsfield?!
OTHERS:
Leave Pottsfield? What?
- Oh, are we leaving already?
- Let's leave immediately.
[Raspy breathing,
crowd muttering]
I'm just trying to get home.
They're not supposed
to be here.
Maybe he's here
to steal our crops.
To ruin our party.
Or take off
our pumpkin shoes!
Uh, no, I, uh...
[deep voice]
Heh heh. Now, hold on, everybody.
Heh. Let's not jump
to any conclusions.
Whoa.
Enoch, what shall
we do with them?
I-I'm clone.
Now, let's see here, boys.
How did you end up
in this little town of ours?
Well, we were trying
to get home.
We came into town
from the woods.
Uh, we saw your farms
and your houses and thought,
"Hey, here's a normal place
with normal people."
And we both stepped
on pumpkins.
Yeah, a-and then we heard
the music from the barn,
and, well, uh...
h-how about we just leave?
Now let me get this straight...
you come to our town,
you trample our crops,
you interrupt
our private engagement,
and now you want to leave?
Uh... yes.
You'll never convict!
You have no proof!
This one's trying to escape!
Let me go!
I don't know these clowns!
Children, it saddens me that
you don't wish to stay here
with us, particularly because
I simply have to punish you
for your transgressions.
I told you this place
was bad news.
ENOCH:
a' So by order of I
[menacing voice]
The Pottsfield Chamber of Commerce,
I find you guilty
of trespassing,
destruction of property,
disturbing the peace,
and murder.
Murder?
[Normal voice]
Oh, no, not murder,
but for those other crimes,
I sentence you to...
a few hours of manual labor.
Wait. What? Really?
That's it?
MAN: J' Among the fields
of straw and stover ♪
♪ Clocked in till
the workday's over I
♪ Time's a gentle stream,
longer than it seems I
♪ Patient is the night a'
♪ How I long to
see her face now a'
♪ Her starry,
moonlit gaze now I
♪ I know she's never late,
still anxiously I wait 4'
♪ Patient is the night a'
[grunts]
Ha ha!
Just a few hours
of manual labor,
and we're almost done.
And then what are
you gonna do...
just wander around
this way and that way
through the woods forevermore?
Uh, uh, maybe we'll just
stay here in Pottsfield.
It's nice here. Heh.
I don't know. I don't know.
Why do they even have you
digging these holes?
Planting seeds or something.
Maybe they're gonna
bury you out here.
Pfft!
Hey! Buried treasure!
Whoa! Really?
See, Beatrice?
What'd you find?
A skeleton!
Aah!
We're digging our own...
I-I-I was wrong.
I was wrong all along.
I-I don't know how
to get us home.
Use your little feet
to pick our locks!
Oh, oh! Now you want my help?
I don't want your help.
Yes, I want your help!
Beatrice, serio...
MAN:
Your time is up!
Aah!
Ohh.
Have the holes been dug?
- Uh, yeah.
- Splendid!
- Well, then...
- But no.
No?
- Uh...
- Psst!
[Metal clinking]
[Muffled]
Keep stalling.
Right. Yeah.
Uh, you know, we were digging,
and there were
too many rocks.
You guys don't like
rocks, right?
- I don't think we do.
- No, we don't like rocks.
I don't think so.
See? So we were like,
"We should get
rid of these rocks."
Well, that's a good idea.
Right? Yeah.
So we were getting rid
of the rocks, and... huh?
Huh? What?
They left me.
So, what happened
to the rocks?
Uh, the rocks.
Yeah, they... they were, um,
you know... they... they...
they got in the way
of all the... well,
the dirt, you know, and...
w-whoa! Ohh!
- Welcome back, Larry.
- He looks exactly the same.
What in the...
LARRY:
Whooooop! Ooh!
[Grunting]
Yeah, Larry! Whoo!
Aah!
Edward, this one's for you!
They're all skeletons.
Thanks for digging up
the life of the party.
ENOCH:
What a wonderful harvest.
And what about you?
You sure you want to leave?
Me? Yes?
Oh, well.
You'll join us someday.
- Uh...
- Psst!
Why are you still here?
What do you mean?
You guys left me!
- Oh.
- Come on.
[Humming]
Oh. Are they chasing us?
- No.
I-I thought you guys...
You're welcome.
Thank you.
I guess we're even now, huh?
You're not honor-bound
to help us anymore.
I wish,
but you weren't actually
in any danger
with those weirdoes.
Oh, yeah! Then you
still have to help us get home.
I got it! I Wish Wirt Jr.
Had fingernails so he could
play the guitar better.
[Crickets chirping]
So... yeah, I'll bring you
to Adelaide.
I mean, that's where
I'm going anyway.
GREG:
Why are you going to Adelaide's?
BEATRICE:
I guess, in some ways,
I'm trying to get home, too.
WIRT:
That's vague. What does that mean?
BEATRICE:
I don't have to tell you anything.
Well, I sure hope Adelaide
is more helpful
than that Woodsman was.
I think his directions
were... not very good.
[Mysterious piano music plays]