[Wind rushing, pastoral music playing]
[Train's whistle blowing]
[Frogs croaking]
GREG".
Home! Home?
Home! Home! Home?
Could be around any corner.
MAN:
♪ Tra-Ia-Ia-la, tra-Ia-la-Ia ♪
[gasps]
Hey, Captain, do you
hear that singing?
- [Croaks]
- Not you, Skipper.
I'm talking to the captain.
- [Croaks]
- Captain Wirt, do you know
Who's singing?
I don't know much
of anything anymore.
Oh. Did you know that
dinosaurs had big ears
but everyone forgot
'cause dinosaur ears
don't have bones?
No. I... I didn't
know that, Greg.
That's 'cause it's not true.
It's a rock fact!
MAN:
♪Tra-Ia-la-la ♪
The beast.
It must be the beast out there.
The obsidian cricket
of our inevitable twilight
singing our requiem.
Hmm. Yeah!
Must be a really fat cricket.
[Thuds]
[Gasps]
[Bugle plays]
Look! We've reached land!
Feel the dirt!
Ahh. Smell that tree.
We must be almost there.
- Greg?
- Yes, Wirt?
Can we please stop pretending
we're gonna get home?
Huh?
Can we admit
we're lost for good?
That this fog is deeper
than we can ever understand?
That we are but wayward leaves,
scattered to the air
by an indifferent wind?
Can we just admit we're never
gonna get back home, Greg?
Can we do that?
Wirt, you can do anything
if you set your mind to it.
That's what the old people say.
Well, then let's do that.
Yes, sir, Captain!
[Bugle plays]
Greg! You need to stop acting
ridiculous all the time.
Huh?
Look, do you even know why
we got lost in the first place?
It's 'cause you were goofing
around and getting into trouble
like you always do.
Really? It was all my fault?
Yeah, so... it's not my job
to get us home, okay? I'm clone.
Are you saying ♪ should
be the leader?
I don't care what you do.
But if I'm the leader...
what are you gonna be?
I'll be asleep.
Wow. Well, then I better
take a nap, too.
I need to dream up a good way
of leading us home.
Thanks for trusting me, Wirt.
Don't worry.
I won't let you down.
I'll be a good leader.
Good night.
[Breathes deeply]
Star, oh, star, up in the sky,
guide my dreams with
light that shines.
Help me know just what to do
to get Wirt home
and also me, too.
And if you don't, I don't care.
I'll pull down your underwear.
[Soft music plays]
WOMAN".
♪ Forward, cherubs ♪
♪ Hear the song ♪
♪ A child's wishes
call us on r
♪ Descend! ♪
Psst! Hey!
[Groans]
Huh? Whoa!
♪ The dreams our
winged wind hath made ♪
♪ For only beneath the veil s
[gasps]
Whoa.
♪ Of sleep ♪
GREG:
Whoooooa! Whoa!
Whoa! Wow!
- Hey, Greg!
- [GaspS]
Nice to see you!
Hey, everybody!
Welcome to Cloud City!
Thank you! Thank you!
My name's Greg.
What are yours?
♪ We're the Cloud City
Reception Committee ♪
♪ And we are here
to welcome thee ♪
[cheers]
Oh, wow, neat.
♪ And we're the Cloud City
Auxiliary Reception Committee ♪
♪ And we are also
here to welcome thee ♪
Thank you.
♪ And we're the hippopotamus,
giraffe, and monkey ♪
♪ And we are committee
number three ♪
Okay. Are there more?
[Scary music plays]
[Thunder rumbles]
Well, that's enough.
[Cheers]
So, what brings you
to Cloud City?
Well, I'm supposed to be a
leader, but I don't know how.
Why don't you
lead our band in a song?
Okay.
[Up-tempo music plays]
♪ Everything is nice
and fine all the time ♪
♪ The softest clouds
and rainbow skies ♪
♪ Ain't gonna lie ♪
♪ We always have the most
spectacular time together ♪
♪ Everyone is sittin' pretty
on top of the weather ♪
♪ Lasso a cloud and make
the flowers grow ♪
♪ Tie them in a bow to throw
at the end of the show ♪
♪ Our songs are
filled with love ♪
♪ The sweetest love ♪
♪ And we can send them
down to you ♪
♪ With a little shove ♪
♪ So hitch a ride
into the sky r
♪ And join our band ♪
♪ Bring harps and lutes,
kazoos, trombones, and flutes ♪
♪ Or just your pots and pans ♪
♪ We can write a little jig
out of the mighty blue ♪
♪ And we will be here
just for you ♪
[off-key note plays]
Hee-hee!
[Notes play]
[Thunder crashes]
Ohh!
Oh, nooooo!
The North Wind is loose!
[All screaming]
MAN: J' Oh, yeah, the ol"
North Wind starts to howl ♪
♪ Puffs up and furrows
his brow r
♪ Now, now,
you better take cover ♪
♪ Lock up those doors ♪
♪ And close the shutters ♪
♪ I say, the ol" North Wind ♪
♪ Yes, he is ♪
♪ He's gonna fight ♪
♪ He's gonna spin ♪
♪ He's gonna pull back ♪
♪ And blow a little more ♪
♪ Until you can't tell
what you came here for ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah ♪
- Fire!
♪ The ol" North Wind,
yes, indeed ♪
♪ He's gonna
breathe and breathe ♪
♪ He's gonna blow ♪
[thunder crashes]
♪ Blow till you can't
feel no more ♪
Wirt? Greg?
Is anyone out there?
[Thunder crashes]
Aah!
[Shuddefing]
[Laughing evilly]
[Thunder crashes]
[All gasp]
[Wind howling]
[Laughing]
Hey, North Wind! Pbht!
[Grumbles]
I don't like that one bit.
That makes me mad!
- [Gasps]
- [Grumbling]
GREG:
Oh, no!
[Crashing, thudding]
[All murmuring]
[Door creaks]
Ha ha!
Hee hee hee hee!
[Cheers]
Huh?
Why, hello, Gregory.
Hello.
I am the queen of the clouds.
Thank you for saving my city.
You're welcome.
I shall grant you one wish.
What do you wish for
most of all?
Well, I'm supposed
to be the leader,
but I don't know
how to get home.
- Do you know?
- Of course.
If you wish, I can
certainly send you home.
Great! Let's go get Wirt.
I'm sorry, Gregory, but
Wirt cannot go with you.
He is too lost.
[Gasps]
But... anything is possible
if you set your mind
to it, right?
See how the edelwood
grows around him?
The beast has
claimed him already.
Oh, I should have
been leading better.
I was goofing off again,
like always,
and now you're stuck here.
Isn't there anything I can do?
I'm sorry, Gregory.
Wirt's fate lies solely
in the beast's hands now.
Then I know what to wish for.
- [Whispering]
- [Gasps]
Are you sure?
Then it shall be clone.
[Ting!]
Hey. Hey, Wirt?
Shh! Trying to sleep.
Okay. You sleep.
I'm sorry I got us lost, Wirt.
Will you take care
of Ronald for me?
Okay. I have to go now.
Good-bye, Wirt.
MAN".
Yes. Come, Gregory.
There is much to be done.
GREG: And then you'll show us
the way home, right?
MAN".
Of course.
We made a promise, didn't we?
Greg. Greg?
Greg? Greg?!
Where did he go?
- MAN: J' Tra-la-la-la J'
- No. No, no, no, no!
Greg?!
[Grunting]
What the heck?
MAN:
♪ Tra-Ia-Ia-la, tra-Ia-la-Ia... ♪
Greg?!
Greg. What did I do?
Greg! Greg!
Aah! Unh!
- [Groans]
- GREG: [speaking indistinctly]
[Gasps]
Huh?
Greg.
Oof! Aah!
[Groaning]
BEATRICE:
Oh! You got him! Pull! Pull!
Is he alive? Wirt!
G REG: Wirt! Wirt?
Gr... eg?
BEATRICE:
Wirt, are you okay? Wirt!
Gr... eg? I-I-I...
Where's Greg, Wirt?
Beatrice?
[Shuddered breathing]
BEATRICE: Wirt. Wirt!
[wind howling]
[Mysterious classical piano music playing]